[{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following compounds of a tin is a strong reducing agent?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["SnCl<sub>2<\/sub>","SnCl<sub>4<\/sub>","SnO<sub>2<\/sub>","SnH<sub>4<\/sub>"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>An alkene may be converted to an alkane by<\/strong><\/p>","options":["halogenation","hydrolysis","dehydration","hydrogenation"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following pollutants is biodegradable?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Plastics","Sewage compounds","Metal scraps","Hydrogen sulphide"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>What is the molecular formula of a compound whose empirical formula is CH<sub>2<\/sub>O and molar mass 180? (H = 1, C = 12, O = 16):<\/strong><\/p>","options":["C<sub>6<\/sub>H<sub>12<\/sub>O<sub>6<\/sub>","C<sub>4<\/sub>H<sub>8<\/sub>O<sub>3<\/sub>","C<sub>6<\/sub>H<sub>10<\/sub>O<sub>5<\/sub>","C<sub>4<\/sub>H<sub>8<\/sub>O<sub>2<\/sub>"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following statements explains why tetraoxosulphate(IV) is regarded as a strong acid?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Tetraoxosulphate(IV) acid is dibasic","The acid is concentrated.","the acid is completely ionized in aqueous solution","Tetraoxosulphate(IV) ions are very reactive"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Zinc displaces copper from an aqeous solution of copper (III)salt because<\/strong><\/p>","options":["copper is a transition element","copper is a moderately reactive metal","zinc and copper have reducing properties","zinc is more reactive than copper"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>To what temperature must a gas be raised from 273K in order to double both its volume and pressure?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["300K","546K","819K","1092K"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The components of universal indicator solution can best be separated by:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["evaporaton","chromatography","crystalization","fractional distillation"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following equations represents the reaction leading to the removal of permanent hardness of water?&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["MgSO<sub>4<\/sub> + Na<sub>2<\/sub>CO<sub>3<\/sub> \u2192  MgCO<sub>3<\/sub> + Na<sub>2<\/sub>SO<sub>4<\/sub>","Ca(OH)<sub>2<\/sub> + 2HCL \u2192  CaCI<sub>2<\/sub> + 2H<sub>2<\/sub>O","Ca(HCO<sub>3<\/sub>)<sub>2<\/sub> + Ca(OH)<sub>2<\/sub> \u2192  2CaCO<sub>3<\/sub> + 2H<sub>2<\/sub>O","MgSO<sub>4<\/sub> + BaCI<sub>2<\/sub> \u2192  MgCI<sub>2<\/sub> + BaSO<sub>4<\/sub>"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>How many mole of AgNO<sub>3<\/sub>, are there in 500cm<sup>3<\/sup> of 0.01M AgNO<sub>3<\/sub> Solution?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["0.005 mole","0.05 mole","0.5 mole","1 mole"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>When napthalene on heating changes from the solid&nbsp; state directly to the gaseous state, it undergoes?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["evaporation","sublimation","decomposition","ionisation"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Nuclear reactions can be used in the following except:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Gauging the thickiness of objects","Making atomic bombs","Curing cancer","Purifying water"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>What quantity of electricity in faraday is required to liberate 9g of aluminium? (Al = 27)<\/strong><\/p>","options":["0.1F","0.3F","1.0F","3.0F"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>If 3 mole of electrons are required to deposit 1 mole of a metal, M during the electrolysis of its molten chloride, the molecular formula of the metallic chloride is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["M<sub>3<\/sub>CI","M<sub>3<\/sub>CI<sub>2<\/sub>","M<sub>2<\/sub>CI<sub>3<\/sub>","MCI<sub>3<\/sub>"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Alkanols have unexpectedly high boiling points relative to their molar masses because of intermolecular<\/strong><\/p>","options":["hydrogen bonding","metallic bonnding","covalent bonding","ionic bonding"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following compounds crytallizes without water of crytallization?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Na<sub>2<\/sub>Co<sub>3<\/sub>","CuSO<sub>4<\/sub>","MgSO<sub>4<\/sub>","NaCI"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Sodium chloride cannot conduct electricity in the solid state because it<\/strong><\/p>","options":["is a normal salt","is highly soluble in water","is an electrovalent compound","does not contain mobile ions"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The products of the electrolysis of dilute sodium chloride solution with platinum electrodes are<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Hydrogen and oxygen","oxygen and chlorine","hydrogen and chlorine","sodium amalgam and chlorine"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following pairs are both substance deliquescent?<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p>&nbsp;<\/p>","options":["CaCl<sub>2<\/sub> and H<sub>2<\/sub>S<sub>4<\/sub>","NaOH and MgSO<sub>4<\/sub>.7H<sub>2<\/sub>O","CaCl<sub>2<\/sub> and NaOH","CuO and NaCl"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Alums are classified as:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["simple salts","acid salts","anhydrous salts","double salts"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The product of the reaction between ethanol and excess acidified K<sub>2<\/sub>Cr<sub>2<\/sub>O<sub>7<\/sub> is;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["ethanal","ethylethanoate","ethanoic acid","ethyne"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following statements is not correct of Group 7 elements?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["They are diatomic","They are good oxidizing agent","They are highly electrongative","They have relatively low ionization Potentials"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>In which of the following processes are larger molecules broken down into&nbsp; smaller molecules?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["vulcanization of rubber","hydrogenation of palm oil","hydrolysis of starch","polymerization"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following statements is not correct? Cathode rays<\/strong><\/p>","options":["are positively charged","travel in straight lines","are deflected away from negative plates","are very light"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>What does the following equation illustrate?<\/strong><\/p><p><strong><br><sup>238<\/sup><sub>92<\/sub>U --&gt; <sup>234<\/sup><sub>90<\/sub>Th + <sup>4<\/sup><sub>2<\/sub>He<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Nuclear fission","Nuclear fusion","Artificial radioactivity","Spontaneous disintegration"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Chlorine is prepared on a large scale by the&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["electrolysis of concentrated sodium chloride solution.","action of manganese(IV)oxide on a hot concerned hydrochloric acid","action of concerned tetraoxosulphate(vi)acid on sodium chloride.","oxidation of concerned hydrochloric acid with potassium tetraoxomaganate(VII)"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Compounds that have the same molecular formula but different structures are said to be<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Isomeric","Isotopic","Polymeric","Allotropic"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>CH<sub>4(g)<\/sub> + 2O<sub>2(g)<\/sub> <\/strong><strong><span class=\"ILfuVd\"><span class=\"e24Kjd\">\u2192<\/span><\/span>&nbsp;&nbsp; 2H<sub>2<\/sub>O<sub>(l)<\/sub> + CO<sub>2(g)<\/sub>&nbsp; &nbsp;\u0394H=890KJ mol-<sup>1<\/sup> \u0394H in the reaction represented by the equation is called the enthalpy of:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["formation","combustion","activation","neutralization"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>When a crystal was added to its solution, it did not dissolve and the solution remained unchanged, showing that the solution was:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Concentrated","Unsaturated","Colloidal","Saturated"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Isotopes of a given element have the same:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Neutron","atomic number","chemical properties","oxidized"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>When steam is passed over white-hot coke, the products are:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Carbon(IV) oxide and nitrogen","Carbon(II) oxide and hydrogen","Carbon(II) oxide and nitrogen","Carbon(IV) oxide and hydrogen"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following statements is correct about catalysts?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["alter the rate of a chemical reactions","are generally specific in action","remain changed chemically at the end of reaction","shift the equilibrium in a reversible reaction."],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>If an element X with the electronic configuration 2,8,3 combines with another Z with electronic configuration 2,8,6 the compound formed will have the formula&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["XZ","XZ<sub>2<\/sub>","X<sub>2<\/sub>Z","X<sub>2<\/sub>Z<sub>3<\/sub>"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The maximum number of electrons that can be accommodated in the shell having the principal quantum number 3 is;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["3","9","18","32"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Methanol is obtained from wood by<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Esterification","Destructive distillation","Combustion","Fractional distillation"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>When an atom gains an electron , it becomes:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["chemically inactive","negatively charged","oxidized","action"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following processes is a physical reaction?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Electrolysis","Hydrolysis","Allotropic change","Neutralization"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>What is the percentage by mass of copper in&nbsp; copper(I)oxide (Cu<sub>2<\/sub>O)?[O=16; Cu=64]<\/strong><\/p>","options":["88.9%","80.0%","66.7%","20.0%"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The following acids are monobasic excep<\/strong>t<\/p>","options":["methanoic acid","dioxonitrate(III) acid","ethanedioic acid","oxochlorate(I)acid"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>''Equal volume of all gases at the same temprature and pressure contain the same number of molecules'' is an expression of<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Charle's Law","Boyle's Law","Graham's Law","Avogadro's Law"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The rate of a reaction is proportional to the number of effective collisions occurring per second between the reactants \"This statement is associated with the&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Kinetic theory","Rate law","Atomic theory","Collision theory"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The following acids are monobasic except:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["trioxonitrate(V)acid","hydrochloric acid","ethanoic acid","tetraoxosulphate(VI)acid"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The most suitable method for preparing lead(II)chloride is by&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["action of dilute HCl on PbSO<sub>4<\/sub>","action of dilute HCl on lead","mixing aqueous solution of Pb(NO<sub>s<\/sub>)<sub>2<\/sub> and NaCl","bubbling chlorine into a solution of Pb(NO<sub>3<\/sub>)<sub>2<\/sub>"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>An arrangement of two different metals in aqueous solutions of their salts to produce an electric current is known as :<\/strong><\/p>","options":["electrochemical cell","activity series","thermocouple","voltameter"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>When iron rusts, it undergoes<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Chemical decomposition","Hydrolysis","Redox reaction","Combustion"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Study carefully the reaction represented by the equation 2H<sub>2<\/sub>O<sub>2(l)<\/sub>&nbsp;&nbsp;<\/strong><strong><span style=\"left: 537.051px; top: 859.523px; font-size: 17.0833px; font-family: serif; transform: scaleX(1.04187);\"><\/span><span style=\"left: 547.83px; top: 854.654px; font-size: 17.0833px; font-family: sans-serif; transform: scaleX(1.13164);\">\u2192<\/span>&nbsp;&nbsp; O<sub>2(g)<\/sub>+2H<sub>2<\/sub>O<sub>(l)<\/sub> Which of the following will not increase the reaction rate?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Heating the hydrogen peroxide","Adding a pinch of MnO<sub>2<\/sub> to the reactant","increasing the concentration of the H<sub>2<\/sub>O<sub>2<\/sub>","Addition of MnO2"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The rate of production of hydrogen gas from the reaction between zinc granules and hydrochloric acid can be increased by:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["cooling the reaction mixture","using zinc powder instead of zinc granules","using zinc rod instead of zinc granules","carrying out the reaction at a higher pressure"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>H<sub>3<\/sub>O<sup>+<\/sup><sub>(aq)<\/sub> + OH<sup>-<\/sup><sub>(aq)<\/sub> 2H<sub>2<\/sub>O<sub>(l)<\/sub><\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>The heat change accompanying the process represented by this equation is the heat of<\/strong><\/p>","options":["neutralization","formation","solution","dilution"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>When sucrose is warmed with Fehling's solution<\/strong><\/p>","options":["a silver minor is produced","Solution turns milky","Brick-red precipitate is formed","There is no precipitate"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>In the reaction represented by the following equation; 2H<sub>2<\/sub>S<sub>(g)<\/sub>+SO<sub>2(g)<\/sub> ---&gt; 2H<sub>2<\/sub>O<sub>(g)<\/sub> + 3S<sub>(g)<\/sub> . &nbsp; SO<sub>2<\/sub><\/strong>&nbsp;<strong> is acting as?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["a reducing agent","an oxidizing agent","a dehydrating agent","a bleaching agent"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Nitrogen is prepared on a large scale by the&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["fractional distillation of liquefied air","decomposition of ammonium dioxonitrate(III)","electrolysis of brine","haber process"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The following salts are readily soluble in water except:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Na<sub>2<\/sub>CO<sub>3<\/sub>","Pb(NO<sub>3<\/sub>)<sub>2<\/sub>","KCI","AgCl<sub>2<\/sub>"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The Ionic radii of metals are usually<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Greater than their atomic radii","Unaffected by the charge on the ion","Less than their atomic radii","Greater than those of non-metals"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following metals will be the most suitable for use where lightness and resistance to corrosion are of importance<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Lead","Aluminium","Iron","Copper"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>What is the amount (in mode) of hydrogen gas that would be produced if 0.6 mole of hydrochloric acid reacted with excess zinc according to the following equation?<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Zn<sub>(s)<\/sub> + 2HCl<sub>(aq)<\/sub>&nbsp;&nbsp; ==&gt; &nbsp; ZnCl<sub>2(aq)<\/sub> + H<sub>2(g)<\/sub><\/strong><\/p>","options":["0.1mole","0.2mole","0.3mole","1.0mole"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following compounds is not a raw material for the manufacture of plastics?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Ethene","Ethane","Monochloroethene","Propene"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The products formed when sodium hydrogen trioxocarbonate(IV) is heated strongly are<\/strong>&nbsp;<\/p>","options":["carbon(IV)oxide and sodium hydride","carbon(IV) oxide and sodium trioxocarbonate(IV)","carbon(IV)oxide and steam","sodium trioxocarbonate(IV),carbon (IV) oxide and steam"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Pipe borne water is usually chlorinated in order to:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Improve the taste of water","remove the hardness in the water","coagulate sediments in the water","kill harmful bacteria in the water"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The energy required to remove the most loosely bound electron from an atom in the gaseous state is known as the<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Bond energy","Ionization energy","Potential energy","Activation energy"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following statement is correct about the following system at equilibrium?<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>PCl<sub>5(g)<\/sub> <\/strong><strong><span class=\"st\">\u2192 <\/span>PCl<sub>3(g)<\/sub> + Cl<sub>2(g)<\/sub>&nbsp;\u2206H positive&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Increase in temperature increases the yield of PCl<sub>5<\/sub>","PCl<sub>5<\/sub> is less stable at high pressure","The concentrations of PCl<sub>3<\/sub> and Cl<sub>2<\/sub> increase at higher pressures","Decrease in pressure favours the forward reaction"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>An increase in the pressure of a gas results in a decrease in its:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["mass","vapour density","volume","concentration"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>An acid is a substance which in the presence of water produces<\/strong><\/p>","options":["salts","oxygen","effervescence","hydroxonium ions"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>If the change in free energy (\u2206G) of a reaction is negetive, it can be deduced that the reaction will<\/strong><\/p>","options":["not proceed in the direction indicated","be reversible","not occur at room temperature","be feasible"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>If a reaction is said to be exothermic, which of the following statements is a correct deduction from the information?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["The reaction vessel gets hotter as the reaction proceeds","\u0394H for the reaction is positive","The rate of reaction increases with time","The activation energy of the reaction is high"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following pH values is likely to be that of a slightly alkaline solution?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["2","5","7","8"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>which of the following ions will migrate to the cathode during electrolysis?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["zinc ions","chloride ions","sulphide ions","Tetraoxosulphate(VI)ion"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following denotes an alpha particle?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["<sup>1<\/sup><sub>0<\/sub>n","<sup>4<\/sup><sub>2<\/sub>He","<sup>0<\/sup><sub>-1<\/sub>e","<sup>9<\/sup><sub>4<\/sub>Be"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>What is the quantity of electrons(In mole)is lost when one mole of iron(II)ions are oxidized to iron(III)ions?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["5 mole","4 mole","3 mole","1 mole"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>In linear molecules, the bond angle is:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["90<sup>o<\/sup>","104<sup>o<\/sup>","180<sup>o<\/sup>","120<sup>o<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following minerals contains fluorine as one of its constituent elements?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Cryolite","Bauxite","Potash alum","Kaolin"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The position of equilibrium in a reversible reaction is affected by<\/strong><\/p>","options":["particle size of the reactants","change in the concentration of the reactants","change in size of the reaction vessel","vigorous stirring of the reaction mixture"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The product of the reaction between propanoic acid and ethanol is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Ethylpropanoate","Ethylethanoate","Methylpropanoate","Propylethanoate"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Ethene undergoes mainly additional reactions because it is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["a gas","a hydrocarbon","unsaturated","easily polymerized"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The reaction between alkanoic acids and alkanols in the presence of a mineral acid is known as&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["specification","hydrolysis","polymerization","esterification"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following accounts for the difference in the mode of conduction of electricity by metals and aqueous salt solutions?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Electrons are present in metals but not in salt solutions","Metals are conductor while salts are electrolytes","Electricity is carried by mobile electrons in metals but by ions in aqueous salts solution","Salts ionize in aqueous solution while metals do not"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>When chlorine is added to slaked lime, the product obtained is&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["bleaching powder","chlorinated water","hydrochloric acid","oxochlorate(I)acid"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>which of the following, when heated strongly in air will leave a metal residue?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["sodium trioxonitrate(V)","potassium trioxonitrate(V)","silver trioxonitrate(V)","lead trioxonitrate"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following methods is suitable for the preparation of an insoluble salt?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Action of an acid on a metal","double decomposition","Neutralization","Action of an acid on a trioxocarbonate(IV)salt"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following solids has a network structure?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Diamond","Iodine","Sulphur","Graphene"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The properties of electrovalent compounds include the following except:<\/strong><\/p>","options":["high melting point and boiling point","conduction of electricity in the molten state","high volatility at room temperature","ionization in aqueous solution"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following pairs illustrates isotopy?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["but-1-ene and but-2-ene","carbon and hydrogen","oxygen and ozone","hydrogen and deuterium"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"}]